Contact

3477857785 (Mobile) angelo.geminiani@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ angelogeminiani (LinkedIn) gianangelogeminiani.me (Blog) www.botika.it (Company)

Top Skills

JavaScript

Java

User Experience

Languages

Inglese

Certifications

FUNDAMENTALS OF DEEP LEARNING FOR MULTIPLE DATA TYPES

FUNDAMENTALS OF DEEP LEARNING FOR COMPUTER VISION (Deep Learning Intitute)

shaping-up-with-angular-js

Isomorphic JavaScript with MEVN Stack

Gamification

Honors-Awards

Innovation Light Hacker

Publications

Chatbot e IA per le Aziende

NFT per PROGRAMMATORI

Marketing Automation & Web4... è iniziata la fine dei Siti Web, App o Ecommerce?

Gian Angelo Geminiani

CTO | Entrepreneur | Business Angel

Greater Rimini Metropolitan Area

Summary

Gian Angelo can help you with technology, can manage team of developers for large projects, can design for you great architectures for framework.

Passionate about technology, robotics and artificial intelligence, he specialized at the NVIDIA Deep Learning Institute and collaborates with Confindustria Romagna as Innovation Manager (MISE).

--

Analyst/Developer:

Go, Java, HTML5, Objective-C, Delphi, .Net, C#, C++, Javascript, Typescript, ActionScript3, SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, ArangoDB, Node.is

Platforms:

Android, iOS, Mac OSX, Windows, Linux

Architect:

UML, Design Patterns, Unit testing, Agile development, Prototyping and wire frame

Manager:

Development team leading; project estimation and business plan; Specialization Area:

AI, Chatbots, NLP, NLU, Conversational Design.

Experience

Moonia

Technical Director

January 2022 - Present (3 months)

Rimini, Emilia Romagna, Italia

The Italian laboratory for the creation and development of NFT.

A team of experts in the technology, tax, legal and creative sectors to guide you in the Blockchain and Crypto world. We share knowledge and experience to offer you effective strategies, we support you from the creation to the marketing of your NFT.

Botika // Alchimisti digitali Founder December 2021 - Present (4 months)

Dogana, San Marino

Ministero dello Sviluppo Economico Senior Innovation Manager January 2020 - Present (2 years 3 months) Rimini, Italia

I'm an Innovation Manager approved by MISE (Italian Ministry of Economic Development).

In Confindustria Romagna I'm a Project Manager working on digital transformation projects or projects of technological innovation.

AccYouRate Group S.p.a.
Chief Technology Officer
March 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 10 months)
Milano

AccYouRate Group S.p.A. is a new group of companies, with Made in Italy skills and technologies. It offers integrated wearable solutions and innovative services for companies, healthcare, defense and sports.

I'm CTO and Project Manager, working with external teams and leading internal development about electronics, firmware and software for wearable solutions in health care or corporate markets.

Geminiani Technologies

Owner

February 2020 - March 2021 (1 year 2 months)

San Marino

Temporary Manager as CTO and Project Manager.

Botika

5 years 1 month

CTO & Founder

October 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 4 months)

San Marino

FunnyGain become Botika.

CEO

January 2015 - October 2018 (3 years 10 months)

Repubblica di San Marino

Co-Founder at Funny Gain, a startup incubated in Techno Science Park of San Marino.

We are working to improve businesses with Artificial Intelligence and Process Optimization.

Discover more: http://www.funnygain.com

Fontanot SPA

11 years 1 month

Digital Innovation Manager January 2015 - January 2020 (5 years 1 month) Rimini, Italia

L'azienda Fontanot pone da sempre un particolare focus sull'innovazione tecnologica, considerandola un importante strumento a supporto della competitività di mercato.

In tutti questi anni di collaborazione con l'Azienda Fontanot, ho avuto l'opportunità di sviluppare specifiche competenze nell'applicazione dell'innovazione tecnologica orientata allo sviluppo di soluzioni software per l'ottimizzazione dei processi produttivi aziendali, per la logistica, per la gestione della rete vendita e la configurazione di prodotto.

Ho progettato e partecipato allo sviluppo di sistemi che fanno uso di Machine Learning per ottimizzare i processi di controllo qualità.

http://www.libertas.sm/notizie/2019/03/03/san-marino-confindustria-seleziona-unazienda-sammarinese-nel-team-smarttech-per-linnovazione.html.

Digital Strategist

January 2009 - December 2014 (6 years)

Created the Web Marketing Department, defined Blog guide lines and Facebook Group strategies.

Developed Enterprise 2.0 tools for departments collaboration and interactions with SAP/R3 ERP.

Refactoring end designing of new intranet and extranet using most recent Open Source Platforms.

Chief of Software Development

January 2009 - December 2011 (3 years)

Overseeing software Research and Development (R&D) activities, and formulating long-term visions and strategies at the officer level. In furtherance of the company's objectives, I try to define best strategies for goals.

Botfarmy

CTO

November 2016 - March 2017 (5 months)

Milan Area, Italy

Building bots and writing lightweight NLP engine.

Our bots can help you reducing customer care costs, improving customer acquisition and engagement, replace boring mailing list end deliver payed contents.

Smartfeeling.org

Project Manager, Information Designer and Blogger January 2007 - January 2015 (8 years 1 month)

Smartfeeling.org is a no-profit organization born to support some free and Open Source initiatives.

All voluntary activities are carried out by Gian Angelo Geminiani.

Sphinner S.n.c

C.E.O.

January 2010 - December 2014 (5 years)

Sphinner is a Software Farm specialized in three areas:

- Solutions (B2B suppliers, sales network, staff)
- Solutions (B2C configurators, social commerce)
- Automation of industrial processes (Data Collection, Intelligence board, RF / ID and traceability)

Albini & Fontanot S.p.A

CIO

January 2008 - May 2009 (1 year 5 months)

Developing a web C.R.M. solution integrated with SAP/R3.

The platform allow access at all registered users (sales force, resellers and internal users) to a wide number of functionalities (i.e. a custom graphical product configurator), customer's data (invoice, unsettled, etc..) news and enterprise communications.

Università di Bologna - Dipartimento di Scienze degli Alimenti Ricercatore

June 2007 - July 2008 (1 year 2 months)

Ho collaborato con la facoltà di Scienze degli Alimenti come ricercatore sul progetto di "Sviluppo di una piattaforma unificata per un sistema avanzato di (rin)tracciabilità dei prodotti ortofrutticoli di IV gamma".

Il periodo di ricerca si è concluso con l'implementazione di una piattaforma web visibile al link www.quartagamma.com. La piattaforma è stata dotata di un algoritmo avanzato e modulare per la rintracciabilità dei prodotti, che consente di risalire a tutto il processo di filiera partendo da uno qualunque dei documenti coinvolti. Le informazioni rintracciate vengono "profilate" in funzione del livello di autorizzazione del richiedente (es: consumatore, ente di controllo, ispettore, produttore, trasformatore, ecc..).

Albini & Fontanot Informatica S.r.l.

6 years

Software Designer and Software Architect January 2007 - December 2007 (1 year)

Interfacing with sponsors and users to determine software needs.

Design software architecture and develop core framework.

Project Manager

January 2002 - December 2006 (5 years)

Manage a team of 5 programmers in development of a new Web 2.0 oriented framework.

Gian Angelo Geminiani Consultant

1998 - 2000 (2 years)

In questo periodo ho collaborato con diverse strutture e realtà aziendali tra cui: Albini & Fontanot S.p.A.: Web project Manager per l'implementazione di servizi Intranet/Extranet integrati al sistema ERP aziendale per la gestione delle informazioni destinate alla rete vendita internazionale.

In questo periodo ho sviluppato anche un configuratore commerciale che è stato distribuito su piu' di 400 Totem (chioschi multimediali per la preventivazione).

Tender Group S.p.A.: realizzato un configuratore tecnico/commerciale basato sulle caratteristiche costruttive del prodotto.

S.I.L.C.E.A. S.r.I.: operato a fianco dell'Amministratore Delegato, Luca Bellucci, come consulente.

Multisoft Informatica S.r.l.: Sviluppatore freelance e Project Manager su diversi progetti.

Con.si.ge S.r.l.: realizzate diverse soluzioni gestionali, tra cui un software per la gestione delle agenzie immobiliari e delle filiali in franchising.

Skylab s.r.l. Project Manager 1997 - 1999 (2 years)

In questo periodo sono stato amministratore di SkyLab S.r.l., una piccola realtà che si occupava di rivendita ed assemblaggio hardware, di consulenza aziendale e di sviluppo servizi Web.

SkyLab era associata a Cento CAD, ed abbiamo operato congiuntamente nell'offrire servizi ad Architetti ed Avvocati sul territorio Riminese.

Silcea IT Manager 1997 - 1998 (1 year)

S.I.L.C.E.A. è un suolificio che opera da diversi anni nel mondo calzaturiero. Con Luca Bellucci (Amm. Del.) abbiamo avviato un progetto di forte riorganizzazione dei processi ed informatizzazione.

In un solo anno siamo riusciti a passare da una gestione completamente manuale del ciclo attivo e passivo, ad una completamente informatizzata, con sistemi di preventivazione integrati ai processi produttivi.

Aetna impianti addetto acquisti 1996 - 1997 (1 year)

Ho lavorato per due anni in diverse aziende del gruppo nell'ufficio acquisti e come informatico di produzione.

E' stata la mia esperienza a contatto con una grossa realtà produttiva ed ho avuto l'opportunità di affrontare sia le problematiche di produzione che di progettazione ed industrializzazione del prodotto.

Education

Deep Learning Institute NVIDIA

Certificate, FUNDAMENTALS OF DEEP LEARNING FOR MULTIPLE DATA

TYPES · (2019)

Deep Learning Institute NVIDIA

Course, FUNDAMENTALS OF DEEP LEARNING FOR COMPUTER VISION \cdot (2019 - 2019)

University of Pennsylvania
Gamification Course, Gamification · (2013 - 2013)

Università Internazionale della nuova Medicina (U.I.M.) Master Degree, Handwriting Psychology · (1990 - 1993)

Università degli Studi di Urbino 'Carlo Bo' Bachelor Degree (Laurea), Comunicazione, Sociologia, Communication, Sociology · (1989 - 1993)